hey everybody welcome to this a one
English listening practice video you can
use this video to train your listening
and comprehension as I speak you ready
so today I'm going to talk about the
weather this is an important topic
because everybody talks about the
weather if you are learning English you
need to know how to talk about the
weather so let's start with sunny
weather sunny weather is my favorite
type of weather when it's sunny outside
I'm happy for me hot weather is better
than cold weather some people don't like
the heat but I don't mind the heat it
can be uncomfortable but for me that's
okay
some places are too hot though for
example the city of Las Vegas is really
hot in the summer I like hot weather but
not that hot in really hot cities you
need to stay inside during the afternoon
in the u.s. most buildings in hot cities
have air-conditioning ok now let's talk
about cloudy days I hate cloudy days
when the Sun is not shining I feel a
little sad because I love sunny days but
cloudy days are normal every city has
cloudy days some cities are always
cloudy like London I can't live in a
cloudy city
I need sunshine do you like sunny or
cloudy days more okay now let's talk
about rainy days for me rainy days are
the worst I love being outside so this
is why I don't like the rain when it
rains I can't do anything outside I have
to stay indoors all day some people
really like the rain my wife likes the
rain but only when she's inside she says
that the sound of the rain is calming I
don't agree
I don't like the sound of the rain it
reminds me that I can't go outside of
course you can go outside when it's
raining but you need to take an umbrella
if you don't have an umbrella you get
wet sometimes it starts raining when I'm
not home and I don't have an umbrella
with me this is the worst I don't like
getting wet also when it rains it can be
dangerous to drive many people have car
accidents when it rains when the streets
are wet you need to drive slower if you
don't you can have an accident
on rainy days there are a lot of car
accidents I don't like driving in the
rain all right now let's talk about
windy days some cities have a lot of
wind and this can be good or bad if you
live in a hot city the wind can be good
because it cools the city down but if
you live in a cold city the wind can be
bad because it makes it even colder if
the wind is really strong it can cause
problems sometimes trees fall down
because of the strong wind usually I
prefer days that aren't windy okay
lastly let's talk about the snow it
doesn't snow in my city so I don't see
the snow often some years my family goes
to the mountains in the winter to ski
and snowboard I like the snow but I
don't want to live in a snowy city it's
too cold and life is more difficult in
the snow I have some students that live
in really cold cities during the winter
the temperature can be minus 20 or minus
30 degrees Celsius for me that's crazy
I don't like the cold another bad type
of weather is stormy weather in the u.s.
we have some bad
storms like hurricanes and tornadoes
I've never seen a storm like this before
but I've seen many thunderstorms
these storms are not that bad but I
don't like lightning lightning can be
scary okay that's all for today leave a
comment and tell me what type of weather
you prefer I'll see you next video
[Music]
[Applause]